Pie charts or pie graphs, I have
mixed feelings about. Some people
love them, some people do not like
them. They are mostly effective
if you have between three to five
categories that you're trying
to display how much of the total
they take up. Now with pie charts
especially, you need to be careful
because as much as we think we're
great at interpreting angles,
which are what pie charts rely on.
Unless there's one category that's
significantly greater than the other
categories, a pie chart's not going
to be as easily interpreted as
we may hope. We can do some things
to help with that. We can display
the percentage that each category
is taking up, but I tend to stay
away from a pie chart and tend to do
a column chart that's been changed
to display 100% and then broken
down by that category just so that
way it's a lot easier for your eye
to see. You're really, your eyes
are a lot better at finding height
differences than angle differences.